Assignment || Full Stack Laravel Developer || weDevs




[N.B. Even if you cannot fulfill all the requirements, we still encourage you to submit the assignment. Good Luck!]

Objective:

Your objective is to create a simple e-commerce system as described in the System Overview section below. You have to use Laravel and Vue/React. You have to create two separate projects: Laravel project for the API and VueJS/ReactJS project for consuming that API. You have to use Laravel JWT or Laravel Sanctum for authentication. You have to use Vuex/Redux for authentication.

System Overview:

Create a minimal e-commerce system.

The system has a single administrator who manages the system. The admin can add, remove or update products. They can also approve, reject or update the status of an order placed by the buyers.

To summarize, the admin should have the following responsibilities:

Add/Remove/Update/ products
See the list of products
Search a product by name
Approve or reject the orders
See the edit history of an order
Search an order by unique ID
Update the status of the order to any of the following: Processing, Shipped, Delivered

Buyers can sign up to the system and place orders to purchase products. The administrator can approve or reject the orders. The buyer can edit the order as long the order is pending. If the order is approved or rejected the buyer cannot edit the order. Both the admin and the buyer can see the edit history of an order.


To summarize, the buyers should have the following responsibilities:

Sign Up/ Log In
See the list of products
Search a product by name
Sort the products by lowest/highest price
Place an order
Edit an order until approved or rejected by the admin
See the edit history of an order
Filter the orders by: Approved, Rejected, Processing, Shipped, Delivered

The system should also fulfill the following requirements:

Products should contain the following fields: Name, Description, Price, Qty, Image.
When an order is placed, the admin should be notified. This is up to you how you want to handle the notification.
When the admin marks an order as delivered, the qty of the product should be updated.
If a product has qty 0 (Zero), the buyer should see an “Out of stock” message in the UI.
If the product is updated by the admin, say for example the admin updated the price, it should not affect the existing orders, meaning that the ordered product should have the price that was set during the order, not the recently updated price.
Every midnight at 12:00AM, all the delivered orders should be moved to a separate “deliveries” table.


Must Have:

This assignment should be completed using the Laravel PHP Framework for the backend and VueJS/ReactJS for the frontend.
The assignment should contain two separate projects for both the frontend and the backend. The backend should serve RESTFul APIs, and the frontend should consume the APIs.
You should not use any heavyweight CSS framework like Bootstrap etc. You have to use:
a) Vanilla css/sass or,
b) Utility-first frameworks like TailwindCSS or,
c) A good mixture of (a) and (b).
The UI should be pleasing to the eye.
The system should be functional with no broken features.
The code should be properly formatted.


Nice to Have:


Proper use of Object-Oriented Programming.
Use design patterns if needed.
Write clean code.
Create documentation for the API. You can use Postman for generating API docs. 


Bonus Points:


If you use TypeScript with Vue/React.
If you write unit tests for your APIs.
If your controllers are clean.
If your functions/methods do not exceed more than 6 lines.


Query Notes
If you have any questions regarding the assignment, drop your query at tanmay@wedevs.com. 
If you have mailed for any query, please be sure your Subject should look like exactly the Subject mentioned below
Subject: Query | Assignment | Full Stack Laravel Developer


(P.S: Follow the submitting process mentioned in the mail)
